The Democratic Party is not progressive and it is not leftist and it does not represent the left politic in this country.
The Democratic Party functions to preserve the status quo of the two party system, capitalism, white supremacy and patriarchy by very effectively quenching and neutralizing the spontaneous revolutionary sentiment that periodically arises in this country.
You have witnessed this repeatedly over the last 10 to 15 years through the spontaneous uprisings that emerged after the murders of Trayvon Martin, Mike Brown, George Floyd, the spontaneous uprising that emerged after the election of Donald Trump.
Every single one of those revolutionary sentiments was effectively quenched by the Democratic Party.
How?
Pandering and symbolic gestures of representation that made you believe that real change was on the horizon.
By continuing to allow the Republican Party to execute each and every one of its promises, the Democratic Party have run out of boogeymen.
They've already let abortion rights lapse.
However, they have not used any of their majorities over the past 30 years going back to Bill Clinton to enshrine abortion rights.
And as a matter of fact, abortion rights have lapsed under the Biden administration for years.
They have said, oh, if you elect the Republicans, they're going to start World War Three and start a war with Iran.
Open your eyes, what is happening right now in the Middle East that is not only funded by the Biden administration, but it is encouraged and it is the explicit policy.